[
    {
        "question": "Among the following options choose the one which shows the advantage of using the JDBC connection pool.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) The advantage of using a JDBC connection pool is better performance.",
        "options": [
            "Using less memory",
            "Better performance",
            "Slower performance",
            "Using more memory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which contains date information.",
        "answer": "Answer:  A) java.sql timestamp contains date information.",
        "options": [
            "java.sql timestamp",
            "java.io time",
            "java.io.timestamp",
            "java.sql.time"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the method of the JDBC process among the following options.",
        "answer": "Answer:  D) addbatch() Is the method of JDBC.",
        "options": [
            "remove()",
            "deletebatch()",
            "setbatch()",
            "addbacth()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The total JDBC product components in Java software provides is ___________",
        "answer": "Answer: B)The total JDBC product components in Java software provides is 3.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total JDBC drivers available is _____________",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Total JDBC drivers available is 4.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can BLOB, CLOB, ARRAY, and REF type columns be updated?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) BLOB, CLOB, ARRAY, and REF type columns be updated in JDBC 3.0",
        "options": [
            "JDBC 1.0",
            "JDBC 2.0",
            "JDBC 3.0",
            "JDBC 4.0"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which driver is known as the thin driver in JDBC?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Type 4 driver is known as the thin driver in JDBC.",
        "options": [
            "Type 1 driver",
            "Type 2 driver",
            "Type 3 driver",
            "Type 4 driver"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "TCP, FTP, SMTP, Telnet are examples of?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) TCP FTP Telnet, SMTP are examples of protocols.",
        "options": [
            "IP address",
            "Protocol",
            "Socket",
            "MAC address"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the class used for connection-less socket programming.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Both datagram packet and datagram socket is used for connection-less socket programming",
        "options": [
            "Datagram packet",
            "Datagram socket",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total TCP/IP ports reserved for specific protocol is._______",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Total TCP/IP ports reserved for specific protocol is 1024.",
        "options": [
            "1024",
            "2048",
            "512",
            "32"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total number of bits in a single IP address?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) The total number of bits in a single IP address is 32.",
        "options": [
            "4",
            "8",
            "16",
            "32"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of Java?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Bytecode is executed by JVM is the correct answer.",
        "options": [
            "Dynamic binding between objects",
            "Use of exception handling",
            "Bytecode is executed by JVM",
            "The applet makes the Java code secure and portable"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the major components of the JDBC?",
        "answer": "Answer: B)The major components of JDBC are - DriverManager, Driver, Connection, Statement, and ResultSet.",
        "options": [
            "DriverManager, Statement, and ResultSet",
            "DriverManager, Driver, Connection, Statement, and ResultSet",
            "DriverManager, Connection, Statement, and ResultSet",
            "DriverManager, Driver, Connection, and Statement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is responsible for getting a connection to the database?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Driver is responsible for getting a connection to the database.",
        "options": [
            "Connection",
            "Statement",
            "ResultSet",
            "Driver"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which file database table configuration is stored?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Database table configuration file is stored in .hbm",
        "options": [
            ".sql",
            ".ora",
            ".hbm",
            ".dbm"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How constructor can be used for a servlet?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Constructor can be used for a servlet by Initialization and a Constructor function.",
        "options": [
            "Initialization and Constructor function",
            "Setup() method",
            "Initialization",
            "Constructor function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the method which is used to start a  server thread.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) run()  is used to start a  server thread.",
        "options": [
            "start thread()",
            "run()",
            "runthread()",
            "start()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the method which is used to find the URL from the cache of httpd.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) servefromcache() is used to find the URL from the cache of httpd.",
        "options": [
            "getfromcache()",
            "findfromcache()",
            "findcache()",
            "servefromcache()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the instance variable of class httpd among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) All of the above are instances variable of class httpd.",
        "options": [
            "Cache",
            "Port",
            "Log",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which method is used to know the host of an URL?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) gethost() is used to know the host of an URL.",
        "options": [
            "findhost()",
            "gethost()",
            "locatehost()",
            "host()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ways is used to communicate from an applet to servlet?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) All of the above is used to communicate from an applet to the servlet.",
        "options": [
            "HTTP communication",
            "Socket communication",
            "RMI communication",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tag is used to execute Java source code in JSP?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Scriptlet tag is used to execute Java source code in JSP.",
        "options": [
            "Expression tag",
            "Scriptlet tag",
            "Declaration tag",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following access modifiers provides the widest scope of visibility for a class member in Java?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) public",
        "options": [
            "private",
            "protected",
            "default",
            "public"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the finally block in a Java try-catch-finally construct?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) To execute code regardless of whether an exception is thrown or not.",
        "options": [
            "To catch and handle exceptions thrown in the try block",
            "To execute code regardless of whether an exception is thrown or not",
            "To define the conditions for handling exceptions",
            "To provide an alternate code path when an exception occurs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total ways to perform exception handling in JSP is ________",
        "answer": "Answer: A) There are 2 Ways to perform exception handling in JSP.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following tags does the JSP page contain?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) JSP page contains both JSP tags and HTML tags.",
        "options": [
            "JSP tags",
            "HTML tags",
            "Both A and C",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of  JDBC is __________",
        "answer": "Answer: C) JDBC stands for Java database connectivity",
        "options": [
            "Java database Communications",
            "Java database concept",
            "Java database connectivity",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following requires fewer resources?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Thread requires fewer resources.",
        "options": [
            "Process",
            "Thread",
            "Both Thread and Process",
            "Neither read nor process"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What decides the priority of the thread?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Thread scheduler will decide the priority of the thread.",
        "options": [
            "Thread",
            "Process scheduler",
            "Process",
            "Thread scheduler"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which is a type of multitasking?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Both A and B are types of multitasking.",
        "options": [
            "Thread based",
            "Process-based",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the RMI server responsible for?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) RMI service is responsible for all of the given options.",
        "options": [
            "Exporting remote object",
            "Creating an instance of the remote of",
            "Binding an instance of the remote object building to the RMI registry.",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "RMI stands for __________",
        "answer": "Answer: B) RMI stands for Remote Method Invocation.",
        "options": [
            "Remote Memory Interface",
            "Remote Method Invocation",
            "Random Method Invocation",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is built on top of socket programming?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) RMI is built on top of socket programming.",
        "options": [
            "RMI",
            "EJB",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify among the following which follows the connectionless service.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) UDP follows the connectionless service.",
        "options": [
            "HTTP",
            "TCP/IP",
            "TCP",
            "UDP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following protocols are used for splitting and sending packets to an address across a network.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) TCP/IP .is used for splitting and sending packets to an address across a network.",
        "options": [
            "SMTP",
            "TCP/IP",
            "UDP",
            "FTP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total number of ResultSet available with the JDBC 2.0 core API?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) The total number of ResultSet available with the JDBC 2.0 core API is 3.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    null,
    null,
    {
        "question": "Among the following identify the packages which represent interfaces and classes for servlet API.",
        "answer": "Answer:  C) Both a and b are correct.",
        "options": [
            "javax.servelet.http",
            "javax.servelet",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the HTTP request method which is non-idempotent.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Both POST and GET are non-idempotent.",
        "options": [
            "POST",
            "GET",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following examples of application servers?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) JBoss is an example of an application server",
        "options": [
            "JBoss",
            "Tomcat",
            "Apache",
            "WebLogic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The total number of techniques used in session tracking is ________",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Total 4 techniques used in session tracking.",
        "options": [
            "3",
            "4",
            "5",
            "6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the Microsoft solution for providing dynamic web content.",
        "answer": "Answer: A) JSP is used for providing dynamic web content.",
        "options": [
            "ASP",
            "JSP",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the difference between servlet and JSP?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) The major difference between servlet and JSP is syntax.",
        "options": [
            "Compilation",
            "Translation",
            "Syntax",
            "Both A and B"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which is not a directive?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Export is not the directive",
        "options": [
            "Page",
            "Include",
            "Tag",
            "Export"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "For resolving Facelet views, which of the following is configured.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) ViewResolver is configured for resolving Facelet views.",
        "options": [
            "View_Resolver",
            "View-resolver",
            "ViewResolver",
            "ViewFacelets"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following methods which of the following returns proxy object.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) load() Is the method that returns a proxy object.",
        "options": [
            "getDatabase()",
            "get()",
            "load()",
            "loadDatabase()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following which attribute is used to specify the class name of the bean.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) class is used to specify the class name of the pin.",
        "options": [
            "id",
            "class",
            "name",
            "constructor-args"
        ]
    },
    null
]